

NAMFON UMSARIKA

Corporate Head CMI (Consumer & Market Intelligence)
Tel +66-897742455

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With 19+ years of experience, I excel in Market and Consumer Intelligence. I drive business growth via digital transformation, market performance evaluation, and strategic thinking. I specialize in data transformation, visualization, segmentation, and brand health tracking. I've enhanced marketing strategies for diverse beauty divisions, utilizing tools like Power BI, Nielsen Advisor, and Kantar World Panel to distill insights for commercial success.

ACHIEVEMENT HIGHLIGHTS:

· Spearheaded a successful digital transformation in research initiatives during 2019-2020, resulting in the modernization of research services and

EXPERIENCE

CORPORATE HEAD CMI · L'OREAL · MARCH 2016 - PRESENT CORPORATE HEAD CMI · L'OREAL · MARCH 2016 - PRESENT

- strategically led market and consumer intelligence for multiple beauty divisions.
- · mentored a team leveraging data sources like Nielsen, kantar panels, and more.
- · applied research techniques, including segmentation and social listening, to solve challenges and unearth opportunities.
- transformed data into actionable insights, driving marketing effectiveness.
- · delivered strategic insights, accelerating channel growth and customer acquisition.
- · identified 3-5-year growth opportunities and market trends.
- · developed dynamic power bi dashboards for comprehensive analysis.
- · evaluated marketing campaigns and retail operations for key brands.
- · supported retailer and ecommerce partner meetings with integrated data.

CONSUMER INSIGHT MANAGER \cdot AB FOOD COMPANY \cdot FEB 2015 TO JAN 2016

- · conduct customized research studies such as U&A, taste/consumer segmentation, and pricing optimization studies to tackle business issues.
- · conduct pre-post evaluations to measure marketing activities.

MARKET RESEARCH MANAGER · NESTLE COMPANY · MAY 2011 TO JAN 2015

- conduct customized research studies such as U&A, taste/consumer segmentation, and pricing optimization studies.
- · explore new marketing opportunities and channels by using research information, Nielsen/market share information, and other sources.
- · facilitate brand strategy workshops for marketers.
- · implement new tools such as brand dashboard and price optimization tool for marketing.







TWITTER HANDLE



66 89 7742455



HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDI N.COM/IN/NAMFON-UMSARIKA-1645A7159/ tools (including social listening and digital tracker), along with the implementation of online community panels.

- · Led ongoing data transformation efforts for Sell Out data since 2020, effectively integrating data from diverse digital platforms, expanding market data coverage, and converting market reports into dynamic Power BI visualizations. Additionally, identified consumer addressable targets for L'Oréal Group.
- Experienced in segmentation techniques and proficient in using Power BI tools.
- · familiar with a range of industry-standard tools including Nielsen advisor/discover, bases/pricing optimization study, kantar world panel, brand health tracking, and marketing mix modeling.

EDUCATION & SKILLS

- MASTER DEGREE · 2006 · NIDA MBE/Financial (3.2)
- Ba Science/Statistic · 2000 · THAMMASAT UNIVERSITY BA Science/Statistics (2.7)
- Fragrance Testing Certification in 2006
- Visual assessment on Skin attributes in Bangkok and India
- Power BI training
- PDPA as mandatory, data security training 2021
- Google Analytic advance training 2020
- Tiktok golden rule upskill master class 2022
- Leading community's masterclass advance 2022
- Advance communication at Phuket 2023

RESEARCH MANAGER · FIRMENICH · 2009-2011

- responsible for all research studies in Thailand and Vietnam
- Both qualitative and quantitative study
- Design methodology to support Sales team for Business partner discussion with clients

MARKETING RESEARCH MANAGER · TRUE CORPORATION · 2006-2009

- Market research study for TrueMove
- Work closely with Marketing on conducting the campaign test for new promotion launch
- Support convergence research study
- Mystery study to strengthen Call Centre service team

CONSUMER TECHNICAL INSIGHT RTC SKIN · UNILEVER THAI TRADING COMPANY · FEB 2000-2006

- conduct customized research studies such as U&A, taste/consumer segmentation, and pricing optimization studies.
- work with R&I China India on product testing with consumers.
- qualitative and quantitative test







